Guide to the Jean Elizabeth Crego Papers, 1923-1999
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The Jean Elizabeth Crego Papers
1923-1999
Crego, Jean Elizabeth
4.0 cubic feet (4 Boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, photographs, clippings, and floor plans from Crego's positions at the Vassar College Alumnae House and as the Vassar College Class of 1932 Correspondent, as well as some personal papers.
Biographical Note
Jean Elizabeth Crego was born on 7 October 1910 to Martin Henry and Meta Meyer Crego. After her graduation from Vassar College in 1932, she went on to work for the College, holding many positions, including Decorating Chairman of the Committee on Alumnae House, the Class of 1932's Correspondent, and as Class President. In 1956, she founded the Crego Lectures in honor of her father Martin H. Crego, as part of the Crego Endowment. On 12 December 2005, at the age of 95 years, Jean Crego passed away.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, photographs, clippings, and floor plans from Crego's positions at the Vassar College Alumnae House and as the Vassar College Class of 1932 Correspondent, as well as some personal papers.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae; Vassar College. Class of 1932; Vassar College. Alumnae House
Document Types:
Photographs; Clippings; Floor Plans
VCL Categories
Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Madeleine Amodio, June 2011.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Alumnae and Alumni of Vassar College, February 2008.
Series List
- Series I. Personal and Miscellaneous
  Series I consists of personal correspondence, pictures, documents, and clippings, as well as material relating to lecture funds.
- Series II. Class of 1932
  Series II consists of documents pertaining to Jean Crego's roles in the Class of 1932. This includes official correspondence and other documents relating to reunions and fundraising.
- Series III. Alumnae House
  Series III consists of material relating to the Alumnae House and Associate Alumnae/i of Vassar College (AAVC).
Container List
- SERIES I: PERSONAL AND MISCELLANEOUS
  - Friends of the Art Gallery (Folder 1.1)
  - Correspondence, Personal, to Mary, and Jean Crego (Folder 1.2)
  - Personal Correspondence (Folder 1.3)
  - Personal Correspondence, Pictures, etc., (2 Folders) (Folders 1.4-1.5)
  - 75th Anniversary Fund Report (Folder 1.6)
  - 75th Anniversary Planning Documents (Folder 1.7)
  - Assorted Clippings, Photos and Correspondence, (3 Folders) (Folders 1.8-1.10)
  - Barbara Bailey Brown Lecture Fund (Folder 1.11)
  - Barbara Bailey Brown Lectures Correspondence (Folder 1.12)
  - Barbara Bailey Brown Lectures (Folder 1.13)
  - Jean Crego Trips, 1972-1973 (Folder 1.14)
  - Polly Bryan Documents (Folder 1.15)
  - Yale/Vassar Documents (Folder 1.16)
  - Assorted Clippings, etc. (Folder 1.17)
  - Martin Crego Lectures (Folder 1.18)
  - Mixed Correspondence and Documents, (2 Folders) (Folder 1.19-1.20)
- SERIES II: CLASS OF 1932
  - VC Tile and Class of '32 Printing Die (Folder 1.21)
  - Information on Class of 1932 Classmates and Families (Folder 1.22)
  - Class Correspondence (Folder 1.23)
  - Class Correspondence (Folder 2.1)
  - 25th Fundraising (Folder 2.2)
  - Correspondence (Folder 2.3)
  - Crego Correspondence with fund Office (Folder 2.4)
  - Speech to Vassar Alumnae, 1957 (Folder 2.5)
  - Fundraising and Donation Documents: Correspondence (Folder 2.6)
  - Class of 1932 50th Reunion Forms, (3 Folders) (Folders 2.7-2.9)
  - 1932 Poems From Vassar Poetry 1930 (Folder 2.10)
  - 70th Reunion, (2 Folders) (Folders 2.11-2.12)
  - 65th Reunion, 6-8 June 1997 (Folder 2.13)
  - 60th Reunion, 1992 (Folder 2.14)
  - 55th and 50th Reunions (Folder 2.15)
  - 50th Reunion, (2 Folders) (Folders 2.16-2.17)
  - 44th Reunion, 1976 (Folder 2.18)
  - Class of 1932 40th Reunion (Folder 2.19)
  - Up to 35th Reunion (Folder 2.20)
  - 1932- 30th Reunion- Photos, Black and White, 1962 (Folder 2.21)
  - 30th Reunion, 1962 (Folder 2.22)
  - 25th Reunion (Folder 2.23)
  - 20th/21st Reunion, 1953 (Folder 2.24)
  - Informal Reunions, 1968-1999 (Folder 2.25)
  - Death Notices (Folder 2.26)
- SERIES III: ALUMNAE/I HOUSE
  - Board Meeting Manual, 1982-1983 (Folder 3.1)
  - AAVC Nominations (Folder 3.2)
  - Revised Report of the Joint Task Force to the Board of Trustees of VC and the AAVC (Folder 3.3)
  - Alumnae House, ca 1990-1999 (Folder 3.4)
  - Alumnae House, ca 1980-1989 (Folder 3.5)
  - Alumnae House Phone Survey (Folder 3.6)
  - AAVC Budget, 1991-1992 (Folder 3.7)
  - House Furnishings, Acct Number 69-100-71, 1983-1984 (Folder 3.8)
  - Lighting- Living Room, 1983-1984 (Folder 3.9)
  - Alumnae House, ca 1980-1989; (3 Folders) (Folders 3.10-3.12)
  - Alumnae House, ca 1970-1979; (3 Folders) (Folders 3.13-3.15)
  - Alumnae House, ca 1960-1969 (Folder 3.16)
  - Alumnae House Publicity Printed Matter, (2 Folders) (Folders 3.17-3.18)
  - Alumnae House- Chart- General Operations Plan- 75th Anniversary, June 1940 (Folder 3.19)
  - Alumnae House, ca 1940-1959 (Folder 3.20)
  - Alumnae House Records- Proposals, 1981 (Folder 3.21)
  - Triptych and 4-Panel Music Screen Cleaning and Repair (Folder 3.22)
  - Repairs Records, 1989-1991 (Folder 3.23)
  - Alumnae House Funding, 1923-1924 (Folder 3.24)
  - Building of Alumnae House- Dedication, 1924 (Folder 3.25)
  - Historical Documents Alumnae House and AAVC (Folder 3.26)
  - Rooms- Floor Plans - Information, Measurements, etc., 1987, 1989, 1991 (Folder 3.27)
  - Financial, 1 July 1990- 30 June 1991 (Folder 3.28)
  - Alumnae House Correspondence, Alumnae House Plans, 1967, 1990, 1995-1997 (Folder 3.29)
  - Alumnae House Fundraising Committee - Fay Gambee, 1994-1998 (Folder 3.30)
  - Alumnae House, 1985, 1997 (Folder 3.31)
  - Alumnae House, 1952-1979; (2 Folders) (Folder 3.32-3.33)
  - Alumnae House, 1971-1983 (Folder 4.1)
  - Alumnae House, 1980 (Folder 4.2)
  - Alumnae House, 1981-1983 (Folder 4.3)
  - Alumnae House, 1982-1983 (Folder 4.4)
  - Alumnae House, 1984 (Folder 4.5)
  - Alumnae House, 1985 (Folder 4.6)
  - Alumnae House, 1986 (Folder 4.7)
  - Alumnae House, 1987 (Folder 4.8)
  - Alumnae House, 1988 (Folder 4.9)
  - Alumnae House, 1989 (Folder 4.10)
  - Alumnae House, 1990-1991 (Folder 4.11)
  - VC Memorial Plaque and Window Hanger (Folder 4.12)